Are you a patriot or a vampire?
Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter is a action, fantasy,
horror film directed by Timur Bekmambetov.
President Lincoln's mother is killed by a supernatural creature, which fuels
his passion to crush vampires and their slave-owning helpers.
Abraham Lincoln, played by Benjamin Walker.
Henry Sturgess, played by Dominic Cooper.
Will Johnson, played by Anthony Mackie.
Mary Todd Lincoln, played by Mary Elizabeth Winstead.
Adam, played by Rufus Sewell.
Jefferson Davis, played by John Rothman.
Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter is a 2012 American horror film directed by Timur Bekmambetov, produced by Bekmambetov, Tim Burton, and Jim Lemley,
and written by Seth Grahame-Smith, who also serves as an executive producer alongside Simon Kinberg, Michele Wolkoff, and John J.
It is based on the novel of the same name by Grahame-Smith, depicting a fictionalized history of the American Civil War with the eponymous 16th president
of the United States reimagined as having a secret identity as a lifelong vampire hunter fighting against a caste of vampiric slave owners.
Benjamin Walker stars as Abraham Lincoln with supporting roles by Dominic Cooper,
Anthony Mackie, Mary Elizabeth Winstead, Rufus Sewell, and Marton Csokas.
Filming began in Louisiana in March 2011, and Henry
Jackman was hired to compose the film's score.
Produced by Bazelevs Company, Dune Entertainment, and Tim Burton Productions, the film was released on June 20,
2012, in the United Kingdom and then two days later in the United States, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received mixed reviews; critics praised the visual style but
criticized the overly serious and inconsistent tone.
The film also failed to meet expectations at the box office, grossing
$116 million worldwide against a budget of $69-$99 million.
The film explores themes of usa president, vampire,
supernatural, steam locomotive, american civil war.
The tone is dark.